Guide to the Historic Photographs and Drawings Collection Photo.002
New York University Archives
- Series I: Oversized Photographs and Drawings
  - Folded Printed Pamphlet for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 11x8.5 folded, printed pamphet- printed in red and blue ink Folded size: 3.75x8.5 Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of William Cullen Bryant for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Edwin Booth for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Samuel Langborne Clemens for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of James Fenimore Cooper for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Robert Fulton for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Joseph Henry for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Washinton Irving for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Edward Alexander MacDowell for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Samuel Finley Breese Morse for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Thomas Paine for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt, deposits and heavy stains- appears as if newsprint rub off onto the mounted image. Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Edgar Allan Poe for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Walt Whitman for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Susan B. Anthony for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Henry Ward Beecher for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion, some black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Grover Cleveland for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion, some black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Peter Cooper for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion, some black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Ulysses Simpson Grant for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion, some black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Alexander Hamilton for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion, some black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of James Kent for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to botton, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion, some black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Franklin D. Roosevelt for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, writing on label in blue and black ink, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion, some black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Theodore Roosevelt for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion, some black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Sylvanus Thayer for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion, some black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Lillian Wald for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion, some black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted photograph of bust of Emma Willard for "New Yorkers in the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 18x24 mounted black and white photograph Recto: paper label adhered to bottom, planar distortion, holes at four corners, heavy surface dirt Verso: string adhered to mounting using pressure adhesive, planar distortion, some black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
- Series II: Glass Plates, 1883-1930
  - Delta Iota Delta, 1911 (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Psi Upsilon Party, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 2)
  - NYU Lacrosse Team, 1883-1884 (Box 1, Item 3)
  - "1909" in Butler Hall, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 4)
  - Student Union and Y.M.C.A., 1909 (Box 1, Item 5)
  - Electric Laboratory, 1912 (Box 1, Item 6)
  - NYU Track - Hurdling, 1906 (Box 1, Item 7)
  - NYU Track, circa 1906 (Box 1, Item 8)
  - Rowing Squad, 1908 (Box 1, Item 9)
  - Zeta Psi, 1910 (Box 1, Item 10)
  - NYU Class of 1894, Hats Off (Box 1, Item 11)
  - NYU Football Squad, 1891 (Box 1, Item 12)
  - NYU Class of 1897 (Box 1, Item 13)
  - Old Washington Square Building, Snow, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 14)
  - NYU Class of 1894 (Box 1, Item 15)
  - Psi Upsilon Group, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 16)
  - NYU Lacrosse Team, 1895 (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Fly Lake, 1909 (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Pisek, Bill, Phillips, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Dentz and, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 20)
  - Tally Ho, 1894 (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Tally Ho, 1894 (Box 1, Item 22)
  - NYU Baseball, 1897 (Box 1, Item 23)
  - NYU Class of 1894 (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Cornerstone Lang Hall, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Y.M.C.A. and Bell Tower, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Coming From Chapel, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Halloween Ducking, 1906 (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Fly Lake, 1909 (Box 1, Item 29)
  - NYU Class of 1894, Hats On (Box 1, Item 30)
  - Old Washington Square Building, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Crew and Shell, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 32)
  - NYU Football, 1909 (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Violet Board, 1894 (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Old Washington Square Building, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 35)
  - Old Washington Square Building, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Original Building, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 37)
  - Original Building, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 38)
  - Old Washington Square Building (Bierstadt), circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 39)
  - Old Washington Square Building, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 40)
  - Philomathean Room, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 41)
  - NYU Track - Broad Jumping, 1906 (Box 1, Item 42)
  - NYU Track - Hurdling, circa 1906 (Box 1, Item 43)
  - Psi Upsilon Group, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 44)
  - NYU Rowing Squad, 1908; There are multiple cracks in the top left-hand corner of this glass plate negative. (Box 1, Item 45)
  - Freshman Sophomore Scrimmage, Oct. 1915 (Box 1, Item 46)
  - Freshman Sophomore Scrimmage, Oct. 1915 (Box 1, Item 47)
  - Halloween Ducking, 1906 (Box 1, Item 48)
  - Phi Gamma Delta House, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 49)
  - NYU Class of 1892 (Box 1, Item 50)
  - NYU Track - Pole Vault, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 51)
  - Old Washington Square Building Cut, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 52)
  - Original Building Detail, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 53)
  - Chapel, Original Building, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 54)
  - Chapel, Original Building, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 55)
  - Bleachers, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 56)
  - Pedagogy Library, Washington Square, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 57)
  - Freshman Sophomore Scrimmage, Oct. 1915 (Box 1, Item 58)
  - Fly Lake, 1909 (Box 1, Item 59)
  - Group of Students, 1906 (Box 1, Item 60)
  - NYU Baseball Nine, 1894; There are multiple scratches and cracks across this glass plate negative. (Box 1, Item 61)
  - Freshman Sophomore Scrimmage, Oct. 1915 (Box 1, Item 62)
  - Running Race, 1906 (Box 1, Item 63)
  - NYU Football, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 64)
  - Library of New York University, University Heights Campus, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 65)
  - NYU Baseball, 1906 (Box 1, Item 66)
  - Founders' Memorial, 1911 (Box 1, Item 67)
  - Residence on Campus, House on Schwab Estate, circa 1910 (Box 1, Item 68)
  - "N.Y.U." on Fence, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 69)
  - Old Washington Square Building, 1908 (Box 1, Item 70)
  - NYU Baseball, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 71)
  - Gym in First Location, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 72)
  - Site of Fort #8, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 73)
  - The Bun, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 74)
  - House of Chancellor Henry Mitchell MacCracken, 1910 (Box 1, Item 75)
  - Psi Upsilon House, 1910 (Box 1, Item 76)
  - NYU Chancellor Elmer Ellsworth Brown, circa 1911 (Box 1, Item 77)
  - "Daddy" Falls, 1910 (Box 1, Item 78)
  - Mechanical Engineering Testing Lab, 1912 (Box 1, Item 79)
  - Delta Upsilon House, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 80)
  - NYU Track - Pole Vault, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 81)
  - NYU Chancellor Elmer Ellsworth Brown, circa 1911-1933 (Box 1, Item 82)
  - Gym, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 83)
  - Spectators at an NYU Sporting Event, circa 1906 (Box 1, Item 84)
  - Physics Room, circa 1890-1910; There is a crack in the bottom right-hand corner of this glass plate negative. (Box 1, Item 85)
  - Drawing Room, 1912 (Box 1, Item 86)
  - NYU Baseball Nine, circa 1890-1910; There are multiple cracks across the top left-hand corner of this glass plate negative. (Box 1, Item 87)
  - Group of NYU Athletes, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 88)
  - Dormitory Room, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 89)
  - Students in Butler Hall, circa 1895 (Box 1, Item 90)
  - Crew in Shell, 1908 (Box 1, Item 91)
  - Zeta Psi House, Old, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 92)
  - Physics Lecture, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 93)
  - Student Dinner, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 94)
  - Untitled, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 95)
  - Library, 1895 (Box 1, Item 96)
  - Greek Department Room, Washington Square, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 97)
  - Pedagogy Office, Old Building, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 98)
  - Junior Law Room, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 99)
  - Chancellor's Room, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 100)
  - Old Washington Square Building, Pot Belly Stove, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 101)
  - Untitled, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 102)
  - NYU Track - Pole Vault, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 103)
  - NYU Baseball Players, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 104)
  - Group of NYU Athletes, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 105)
  - NYU Track Athletes, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 106)
  - NYU Track - Shot Put, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 107)
  - NYU Track Athletes, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 108)
  - NYU Track Athletes, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 109)
  - Group of NYU Athletes, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 110)
  - NYU Track Athletes, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 111)
  - NYU Track, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 112)
  - NYU Track Athletes, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 113)
  - The Cross, Chester, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1, Item 114)
  - View from Wash. Bdge., 1890 (Box 2, Item 1)
  - University Heights Railroad Platform, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 2)
  - Northwest View from Physics Building, Butler Hall, 1910 (Box 2, Item 3)
  - Westward View from South Roadway of the Hall of Fame for Great Americans, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 4)
  - General View, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 5)
  - General View, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 6)
  - Untitled, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 7)
  - View Across University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 8)
  - Chas. Butler Hall, View From Northwest, 1909; There is a crack across the top right-hand corner of this glass plate negative. (Box 2, Item 9)
  - N.Y. Skin and Cancer Hospital, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 10)
  - Gould Memorial Library Entrance, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 11)
  - Gould Memorial Library, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 12)
  - Gould Memorial Library, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 13)
  - Gould Memorial Library, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 14)
  - Gould Memorial Library, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 15)
  - Gould Memorial Library, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 16)
  - Gould Residence Hall, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910; The top right-hand corner of this glass plate negative is broken and very sharp. (Box 2, Item 17)
  - Chemistry Lab, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 18)
  - Tablet on Chemistry Building, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 19)
  - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 20)
  - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 21)
  - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 22)
  - View of University Heights Campus from across the Harlem River, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 23)
  - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 24)
  - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, University Heights Campus, View From Southwest, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 25)
  - Havemeyer Hall, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 26)
  - Hall of Languages, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 27)
  - Hall of Languages, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 28)
  - Hall of Languages, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 29)
  - Hall of Philosophy, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 30)
  - Main Estate, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 31)
  - Schwab House, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 32)
  - Schwab House, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 33)
  - Department of Biology, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 34)
  - Untitled, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 35)
  - Students on Campus, University Heights, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 36)
  - Students on Campus, University Heights, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 37)
  - Students on Campus in snow, University Heights, circa 1909-1910; There are multiple cracks across this glass plate negative. (Box 2, Item 38)
  - Students on Campus, University Heights, circa 1909-1910; There is a verticle crack across the right-hand side of this glass plate negative. (Box 2, Item 39)
  - Students in Front of Gym, University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 40)
  - Sports - Track, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 41)
  - Sports - Taking Photo of Event, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 42)
  - NYU - Map of Locations in New York City, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 43)
  - NYU - Map of Locations in New York City, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 44)
  - NYU - Map of Locations in New York City, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 45)
  - Organ at University Heights Campus, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 46)
  - Horse Drawn Carriage on Fifth Avenue, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 47)
  - New York Stock Exchange Exterior, circa 1909-1910 (Box 2, Item 48)